#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/md-faisal-khondhaker-030b6310b (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Team Management
Internal Audit
BSCI

#### Certifications

SA8000 Introduction & Basic Auditor Training Course

# Md. Faisal Khondhaker

Compliance Auditor at PDS Multinational Group,( Simple Approach Limited) Bangladesh

Bangladesh

## Summary

Having more than 7+ years Practical experiences in various types of stakeholder as auditor & auditee .Conducted more than 400 + audit(Social compliance, Environment, Safety, security & technical) in different types industries such as RMG, Footwear, Leather wear industries. Detail-oriented, self-driven & lead companies by ensuring they are functioning in complete compliance with all national and international rules and regulations. Possess excellent communication skills, allowing for the cultivation of positive and mutually beneficial business relationships, while keeping strong ethics at the forefront of my goals.

## Experience

PDS Multinational Group, Bangladesh Compliance Auditor February 2020 - Present (2 years 7 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

- # Responsible to maintain social compliance standards for Primark, Kroger & Giant Tiger etc.
- # Prepare monthly, quarterly and annual performance reports for various internal and external audiences.
- # Build an internal controls system to ensure risks / issues are addressed timely and progress reported regularly.
- # Research, prepare and track corporate social responsibilities and those of our partner factories.
- # Develop communication and coordination with business team for sourcing business partner.
- # Keep track of new customer requirements and updates and work with internal stakeholders to address and adjust practices accordingly.
- # Regularly conducting initial audit, follow-up audit of social, technical & safety (ACCORD and ALLIANCE) as well as environmental audit.
- # Report functionally to organization board. This reporting provides each individual their responsibilities effectively.

Centro Tex Limited
Compliance Officer
February 2018 - February 2020 (2 years 1 month)
Uttara, Dhaka

# In my career I have conducted more than 370 Social Conducting social compliance audits & Technical audits for prominent brand like- Primark, K-mart, Inditex, The Warehouse Group, The Just Group, PEPCO, LPP, Morrisons, BIG-W, Salling group etc.

- # Around more than 100+ factories to develop for social & technical audit like-BSCI, SEDEX, ICS, GOTS, WCA, Better work etc.
- # Creating new opportunity to extend business through develop new factory.
- # Track social and environmental sustainability goals and KPIs, evaluate performance and support continuous improvement.
- # Regularly conducting initial audit, follow-up audit of social, technical & safety (ACCORD and ALLIANCE) as well as environmental audit.
- # Report functionally to organization board. This reporting provides each individual their responsibilities effectively.
- # Function relative to a board approved program. A board approved charter documents the established authority.
- # Conduct at least 01 full follow up audit in every 03 months in all existing factories.

#### Pride Group

Sr.Executive HR & Compliance March 2013 - February 2018 (5 years)

Terranova, Etam, El-Corte, Express, Telly-Weijl, LPP, NEW LOOK, Matalan etc.

- # Developing the HR plans and polices in conjunction with the company's objectives.
- # To facilitate audit like BSCI, SEDEX, WRAP for different kinds of buyer.
- # Manage all renewal license/certificates/permits.
- # To implement & monitor ACCORD /ALLIANCE remediation plan.
- # Developing & implementing disciplinary process and employee welfare services.
- # Co-operate with floor staff to prepared Corrective Action Plan on non-compliance issue.
- # Prepare and submit report as required of management.
- # To find out the non-compliance issue by conducting the internal audit in the factory.
- # Make audit related documentation prior of different buyers.

# Apart from general HR administration, also responsible for a range of tasks.

## Education

Bangladesh Institute of Management (BIM)

Post Graduate Diploma in Human Resource Management, Human Resource Management · (2014 - 2015)

International Islamic University Chittagong
Master of Business Administration (MBA), Human Resource
Management · (2011 - 2012)

International Islamic University Chittagong
Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA), Human Resource
Management · (2007 - 2011)

Ispahani Public School & College, Comilla. Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC), Business Studies · (2004 - 2006)

Feni Govt. Pilot High School SSC, Business Studies · (1999 - 2004)